Guide to the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies Library, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Forestry and Environmental Studies Library, Yale University, records
1900-1998
RU 1119
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.5
(3 boxes)
The School of Forestry and Environmental Studies Library records consist of accession lists, annual reports, classification files, library guides, photographs and a plaque honoring Dr. Frances Mary Bolton.
Yale University. School of Forestry and Environmental Studies. Library
General
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-D (YRG 32-D), Records of Yale school and departmental libraries and collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was transferred by the Forestry and Environmental Studies Librarian, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
These records are restricted until January 1, 2033 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. Please refer to http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives for more details about these policies.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The School of Forestry and Environmental Studies Library records consist of accession lists, annual reports, classification files, library guides, photographs and a plaque honoring Dr. Frances Mary Bolton.
Biographical / Historical
The School of Forestry Library was established in Marsh Hall with the founding of the school in 1900. The core of the collection was donated by the first dean of the school, Henry S. Graves. Graves is also credited with developing the library's first classification scheme, known as Yale Forestry Classification. The library was renamed the Henry S. Graves Memorial Library in honor of Graves in 1953. The school itself was later renamed the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies and the library was often referred to as the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies Library. The library moved in 1923 to Sage Hall and again in 2009 to Kroon Hall where it remained until it closed in 2010 to become part of the Center for Science and Social Science Information.
Academic libraries; Forestry schools and education; Bolton, Frances Mary, 1904-1966; Graves, Henry Solon, 1871-1951; Yale University. School of Forestry and Environmental Studies. Library
- Records, 1900-1998; Accession 2013-A-010
  Conditions Governing Access
  The records are restricted until January 1, 2033.
  - Yale University School of Forestry Library, Catalogue and Accession Lists, 1904-1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yale University, School of Forestry Library, Forestry Library Accession Lists, 1916-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yale University, School of Forestry Library, Forestry Library Accession Lists, 1926-1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Yale University, School of Forestry Library, Forestry Library Accession Lists, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yale University, School of Forestry Library, Forestry Library Accession Lists, 1933-1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Yale University Forestry Library List of Accessions no. 312, June 3-7, 1974 through no. 535, April 27, 1981, 1974-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Henry S. Graves Memorial Library, School of Forestry, Yale University List of Accessions, no. 1, September 15-17, 1969 through no. 311, May 27-31, 1974, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Yale University, School of Forestry Library, Bibliographies on Forestry Subjects by the Librarians, 1915-1948 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Yale University, School of Forestry Library, Reports of the Library, 1911-1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Yale University, School of Forestry Library, Reports of the Library, 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Yale University, School of Forestry Library, Reports of the Library, 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Yale Forestry Library Handbook, 1958-1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Yale Forestry Library Classification, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Frances Mary Bolton - eulogy, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Forestry Library. Yale University, Serials List, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Yale School of Forestry Library, Sample Catalogue, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Classification of Literature on Forestry and Allied Subjects, 1920-1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Eleven publications on classification and lists from Yale Forestry Library, 1912-1962 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Classification of Literature on Forestry and Allied Subjects, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - An Introduction to the Henry S. Graves Memorial Library, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Yale Forestry School Library, List of Titles of Theses and Dissertations, 1900-1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Theses Accepted for Degrees/Dissertations, 1952-1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Photo: Yale Forestry Library in 1904 (Marsh Hall) in: Indian Forester, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Guides to the Yale Forestry Library, 1982?-1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Questionnaires for Library Planning Project, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Library Planning Project - 2 drafts, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Floor plan original pencil drawing Sage Hall library rooms, [1982] (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Arrangement of Books on the Shelves and Classification, Yale Forestry Library, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Yale Forestry School, Maintenance Manual for Card File of Forestry Abstracts, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Yale Forestry Library Current Periodicals, 1957, 1963, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Guides to the Henry S. Graves Memorial Library, 1956-1966 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Instructions to Library Monitors, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Yale University Forestry Library. Henry S. Graves Memorial Library Handbook, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Plaque honoring Frances Bolton, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Forestry & Environmental Studies Library - List of Journals, Periodicals, and other Serials, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Forestry and Environmental Studies Library, Yale University, Management and Development Plan 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Yale Forestry Library Master Plan: Final Report of the Library Planning Project, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Photo album: "Trip to Hell Gate, July 1914 - Foresters of Eastern States and Guests" (Box 3)
    General
    Photographs were taken at the Tonto National Forest in Payson, Arizona.